{"cpp":[[{"question":"which of the following is false about C programming language?","snippet":"\n\n","option_01":"C is a compiled language ","option_02":"C supports access specifiers ","option_03":"C supports struct","option_04":"C supports user defined data types","answer":"2","explaination":""},{"question":"which of the following is false about C and CPP programming languages?","snippet":"\n\n","option_01":"C and CPP support structs","option_02":"C and CPP provide user defined data types","option_03":"C and CPP support inheritance ","option_04":"C and CPP support pointers mechanisnm","answer":"3","explaination":""},{"question":"which of the following is false about inline functions in CPP programming language?","snippet":"\n\n","option_01":"inline functions are faster than normal functions ","option_02":"inline function interrupts the main function and a return address will be given when called","option_03":"CPP supports inline functions","option_04":"the Keyword 'inline' is used while defining inline functions","answer":"2","explaination":""},{"question":"which of the following is false about C language ?","snippet":"\n\n","option_01":"C is a compiled language ","option_02":"Dynamic memory can be requested using 'new' keyword","option_03":"C supports user defined data types","option_04":"C supports structs ","answer":"2","explaination":""},{"question":"which of the following is true about C language?","snippet":"\n\n","option_01":"C supports object oriented programming","option_02":"C supports polymorphism ","option_03":"memory has to be cleared manually in C","option_04":"C is dynamically typed language ","answer":"3","explaination":""},{"question":"which of the following is known as scope resolution operator?","snippet":"\n\n","option_01":"?:","option_02":"::","option_03":"->*","option_04":":*","answer":"2","explaination":""},{"question":"how many basic loops are available in C?","snippet":"\n\n","option_01":"1","option_02":"2","option_03":"3","option_04":"4","answer":"3","explaination":""},{"question":"which of the following is false about C and CPP?","snippet":"\n\n","option_01":"it can access memory address of local storage","option_02":"it can handle file system","option_03":"it can access memory address of registers","option_04":"it can update values directly using address","answer":"3","explaination":""},{"question":"select the odd one out considering C programming Language ","snippet":"\n\n","option_01":"int ","option_02":"float","option_03":"char","option_04":"boolean","answer":"4","explaination":""}],[{"question":"predict the output for the following code snippet?","snippet":"\n\n#include<stdio.h>\nint main(){\nint i=-1;\ndo{\nprintf(\"%d\",i);\n}while(i>0);\nreturn 0;\n}","option_01":"0","option_02":"1","option_03":"syntax error","option_04":"-1","answer":"4","explaination":""},{"question":"predict the output for the following code snippet?","snippet":"\n\n#include<stdio.h>\nint main(){\nint a=2,b=4;\nif(a&b)\n{\nprintf(\"1\");\n}\nelse{\nprintf(\"2\");\n}\nreturn 0;\n}","option_01":"1","option_02":"2","option_03":"runtime error","option_04":"syntax error","answer":"2","explaination":""},{"question":"predict the output for the following code snippet?","snippet":"\n\n#include<stdio.h>\nint main(){\nint a=2;\nif(a==2)\nprintf(\"1\"),a+=1;\nelse if(a==3)\nprintf(\"2\"),a+=1;\nelse\nprintf(\"3\");\n\n}","option_01":"1","option_02":"12","option_03":"runtime error","option_04":"123","answer":"1","explaination":""},{"question":"predict the output for the following code snippet?","snippet":"\n\n#include<stdio.h>\nint main(){\nint a=5,sum=0;\nwhile(a--){\nsum+=a*sum;\n}\nprintf(\"%d\",sum);\nreturn 0;\n}","option_01":"15","option_02":"120","option_03":"runtime error","option_04":"0","answer":"4","explaination":""}]],"java":[],"react":[],"js":[],"ds":[],"algo":[],"dbms":[],"cn":[],"html":[],"aptitude":[[{"question":"what is the average of first five multiples of 12?","snippet":"","option_01":"36","option_02":"38","option_03":"40","option_04":"42","answer":"1","explaination":""},{"question":"What is the difference in the place value of 5 in the numeral 754853?\n\n","snippet":"","option_01":"49500","option_02":"49950","option_03":"45950","option_04":"45900","answer":"2","explaination":""},{"question":" What is the compound interest on Rs. 2500 for 2 years at rate of interest 4% per annum\n","snippet":"","option_01":"200","option_02":"210","option_03":"204","option_04":"300","answer":"3","explaination":""},{"question":" A, B and C are partners. They have invested Rs.35000, Rs. 25000 and 10,000 respectively for the same period. If the total profit is Rs. 18000, find the share of A.","snippet":"","option_01":"9500","option_02":"10000","option_03":"9000","option_04":"8500","answer":"3","explaination":""},{"question":" A's and B's shares in a business are in the ratio of 5:3. If A has invested Rs. 70000 for 12 months, for what period B has invested Rs. 60000?","snippet":"","option_01":"8","option_02":"8.4","option_03":"9","option_04":"9.4","answer":"2","explaination":""},{"question":" Suresh started a business by investing a certain amount of money. Rakesh joined him after four months by investing Rs. 50000. If after one year Suresh and Rakesh share the profit in the ratio of 10:8, how much capital did Suresh invest?","snippet":"","option_01":"42000","option_02":"44000","option_03":"47000","option_04":"41666.7","answer":"4","explaination":""},{"question":") A and B enter into a partnership by investing Rs.14000 and Rs. 16000 respectively. After 8 months, C joins them with a capital of Rs.12000. Find the share of C in a total profit of Rs. 57000 after 2 years.\n\n","snippet":"","option_01":"Rs.12000\n","option_02":"Rs.12500\n","option_03":"Rs.13000\n","option_04":"Rs.13500","answer":"1","explaination":""},{"question":" Mahesh and Suresh rent a pasture for 12 months. Mahesh puts in 200 cows for 8 months. How many cows can Suresh put in the pasture for the remaining 4 months if he pays 1(1/2) as much as Mahesh?","snippet":"","option_01":"600","option_02":"700","option_03":"500","option_04":"550","answer":"1","explaination":""},{"question":" X and Y enter into a partnership for a year. X invests Rs. 6000, and Y invests Rs. 8000. After 4 months, they admit Z, who invests Rs. 9000. If Y withdraws his contribution after 6 months, how would they share a profit of Rs 1000 at the end of the year?","snippet":"","option_01":"300,275,300","option_02":"375, 250, 375\n","option_03":"400, 300, 300\n","option_04":"100, 600,300\n","answer":"2","explaination":""},{"question":" Praveen and Sunny enter into a partnership. Praveen puts in Rs. 50 and Sunny put in Rs. 45. At the end of 4 months Praveen withdraws half of his capital, and at the end of 6 months, Sunny withdraws half of his capital. Ashu Bhati then enters with a capital of Rs. 70. At the end of 12 months, in what ratio will the profit be divided?","snippet":"","option_01":"65:32:56\n","option_02":"54:60:66\n","option_03":"84:82:80\n","option_04":"80:81:84\n","answer":"4","explaination":""}]],"reasoning":[],"numerical":[]}